<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Programming | Zack's Quest]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-20T11:25:10+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Talkative Developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/the-talkative-developer/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T15:33:43+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/the-talkative-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your job scope requires you to sit behind a huge monitor and bury yourself in code. That basically means you build things, in CODE. And what the code renders, is ART. Interactive art and possibly the most modern, most advanced art form.</p>

<p>As developers, we need to be very talkative about the project we are working on.</p>

<h3>Talk to relevant stakeholders.</h3>

<ul>
<li>Your client, your managers, your peers, tell them what you are doing, solicit feedback.</li>
<li>Tell them your vision.</li>
<li>Tell them what you think would work or won't.</li>
<li>Don't wait till the end to start talking.</li>
<li>Keep communicating. Keep telling.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Talk to other developers.</h3>

<p>Again, tell them what you are doing.
* What technology you are using.
* What language?
* What kind of workflow?
* What have you learned?
* What insights do others have to help improve on the project?</p>

<p>Talk.</p>

<h3>Talk to the public.</h3>

<p>You are Working on an amazing thing. Share what you are doing. Do a show n tell and mostly show how much you love the art you produced.</p>

<ul>
<li>Why do you love it?</li>
<li>Was it the process?</li>
<li>The experimental technology you used?</li>
<li>The people/brand/product behind it?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>Don't be a cubicle drone developer. Be a show and tell developer.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noobs should love Coffeescript in Rails 3.1, not hate]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/noobs-should-love-coffeescript-in-rails-3-1-not-hate/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-25T17:40:59+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/noobs-should-love-coffeescript-in-rails-3-1-not-hate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I looked at Coffeescript code and loved the neatness and cleanliness of it. So I kept wondering why I read about backlash when it was announced as the standard for Rails 3.1. I did a bit of research and realized that most developers didn't want to make big changes to their boiler templates or come up with new ones and opting out through the gemfile was not intuitive. (Or at least these were some of the arguments)</p>

<p>The other was that new people learning Rails would be confused. This I definitely do not agree with because the way that Coffeescript translates to Javascript looks pretty intuitive and the language is easy for new learners to read and understand. I don't think it is going to be a barrier for newbies.</p>

<p>I personally like it. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
