<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-13T17:53:43+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Verbs are the next big thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/07/verbs-are-the-next-big-thing/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T11:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/07/verbs-are-the-next-big-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2478/3842546304_8c18b824ea.jpg" title="Four Storms And A Twister by JD Hancock under Attribution 2.0 Generic (CC BY 2.0)" alt="Four Storms And A Twister" /></p>

<p>We have seen the value of Likes from the <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1813364/inside-facebook-si-ipo-filing-845-million-users-37-billion-in-revenues-in-2011">S1 filing of Facebook</a> just last week. Facebook has built a multibillion dollar business by understanding what their users say they like, but more importantly they have incorporated <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/opengraph/">Verbs</a> in order to add more context to their users&#8217; status updates.</p>

<p>The reason for them doing this is simple really. You can talk about what you Like and think all day but it simply doesn&#8217;t mean you will act on it. What is a much better indicator of possible behavior is a user&#8217;s prior behavior. Being able to understand the context of what users are doing will allow advertisers to target users even more accurately.</p>

<p>That is because if you listen to a certain type of music or watch a certain genre of movies frequently, chances are high that you would listen to the same type of music or watch the same genre of movie. Same goes for most lifestyle activities we engage in. Personal preferences are best understood through past behavior.</p>

<p>Activity tracking will be the future and privacy will be compromised. However, in a web eco-system where the social layer drives increasing amount of activity, it is bound to happen.</p>

<p>Activity tracking is not entirely a bad thing however because it provides metrics that provide deeper insights into human behavior and will help us make progress as a species.</p>

<p>In fact, if we are able to create a gamified tracking system that intrinsically rewards users, we will be able to solve much bigger real world problems together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I quit my job to start a company: Focus]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/03/why-i-quit-my-job-to-start-a-company-focus/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-03T11:40:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/03/why-i-quit-my-job-to-start-a-company-focus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People have often advocated starting a new business during my own free time while I&#8217;m holding a full time job before jumping into it. Sure, it means stability and lower risks since I would probably be able to determine whether the business idea will work out.</p>

<p>However, the fact is that a very important aspect of building a good business is actually the founders&#8217; ability to maintain a laser sharp focus on their vision and being able to execute the steps required to reach that vision.</p>

<p>Flow is a state of extremely high focus during an activity and it takes time to get into that state. Every time we switch from one activity to another, we break the flow and our productivity takes a huge beating. Activities that require high focus should be done with as little disturbance as possible.</p>

<p>A day job acts as a daily disturbance to an activity you should be fully committed to and focused on. While holding a day job now, I spend 3 hours a day traveling and 9 hours at the office (sometimes more). That is a total of 12+ hours a day spent not working on my product. Most of my energy get expended during those 12 hours as well and I reach home battered and depleted.</p>

<p>How can I convince the world that I believe in my vision if I am unwilling to dive into it and place my full commitment and focus on the business?</p>

<p>If you are starting a business right now while also working a full time job, stop kidding yourself. You are moving much slower than you should be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Double standards of the old and crumbling media industry]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/20/double-standards-of-the-old-and-crumbling-media-industry/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-20T11:17:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/20/double-standards-of-the-old-and-crumbling-media-industry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8216;Unfortunately, some groups believe that speech or ideas that they disagree with should be silenced. This could not be more wrong. No matter the point of view, everyone has a right to be heard.&#8221;  &#8211; MPAA</p>

<p>MPAA should stop being such a troll. Isn&#8217;t this what SOPA / PIPA was for? So big organizations can silence people but no one can silence the big organizations?</p>

<p>Hacking major sites like yours may not be the best course of action but it has certainly shown the double standards.</p>

<h4>Full Statement from the MPAA:</h4>

<p>&#8220;Our website and many others, including the Department of Justice, were attacked today and the hacker group Anonymous is claiming responsibility for the attacks. We are working with law enforcement authorities to identify those responsible.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, some groups believe that speech or ideas that they disagree with should be silenced. This could not be more wrong. No matter the point of view, everyone has a right to be heard.</p>

<p>The motion picture and television industry has always been a strong supporter of free speech. We strongly condemn any attempts to silence any groups or individuals.</p>

<p>The Internet is home to creativity, innovation and free speech. We want to keep it that way. Protecting copyrights and protecting free speech go hand in hand.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time stopped momentarily, I took a glance back at 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/time-stopped/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-15T04:17:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/time-stopped</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reflection is the first step for improvement. Without spending time to figure out what to learn and improve on, we fall into the danger of stagnation. This may come a little late but it must be done. Let&#8217;s take a look back at my 2011.</p>

<h3>1. Toy with idea of Gamification</h3>

<p>It was the beginning of a new year. Being an RPG lover, I started imagining living my life as if it was an RPG, gaining levels while completing quests and achievements.</p>

<p>I was sure it was a novel idea but some research proved that it was not. SCVNGR was the biggest real life Gamification service at that time.</p>

<p>My first thought was that I wanted to marry Gamification with instagram&#8217;s stickiness as an app. Sourcing for funding was a tough matter at that time and I was unsure how to move the idea forward. It probably sucked anyway, as all who have experience in tech startups would tell you about your initial idea.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: Fund raising is a difficult process for early stage ideas and first time founders. Get a working prototype out!</p>

<h3>2. Account executive work</h3>

<p>I continued my work as an account executive and learned a lot about customer service and project management, though project management was mostly planning what the client wanted.</p>

<p>During this time, I also discovered my love for coding as I made amendments to my developers&#8217; code due to tight timelines.</p>

<p>I loved building things. I knew this subconsciously but I was afraid of failing as I never had prior experience, but I took my first step towards development by asking for a switch of department.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: If you want something, dare to ask for it. If you never take that step, no one can help you get what you want.</p>

<h3>3. Hunger to be a web developer</h3>

<p>I was filled with the hunger to develop for the web and devoured knowledge of HTML5 &amp; CSS3 like a famished vulture. I began picking up jQuery for how easy it was to add interaction to sites and I slowly transitioned into the role of a web developer.</p>

<p>I had little time to sleep as I juggled the extra load of learning but I thoroughly enjoyed the learning process.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: Coding is a creative and iterative process. It takes awhile to get the code right sometimes but the winning sensation is immensely gratifying.</p>

<p>Also, coder&#8217;s block is extremely dangerous and causes me to visit Hacker News more times than I should.</p>

<h3>4. Founder Institute</h3>

<p>During the last quarter of 2011, I received news that I got accepted into Fall 2011&#8217;s SG FI batch. I jumped on the opportunity with only the slightest of hesitation. (ok, just a bit of research on Quora before I paid the course fees.)</p>

<p>Q4 of 2011 would prove to be the toughest period of 2011 for me as I juggled the course schedule, the assignments and an intensive work schedule on my day job doing web development. Few hours of sleep with lots of late night discussions, brainstorming and coding became the norm.</p>

<p>It is paying off now as I am about to start working on Questified full time, taking the full plunge into entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>Founder Institute has been the forceful helping hand that&#8217;s pushing my non-functioning aircraft off the edge. I am all ready to start the sprint to make sure the air craft can fly before it hits the ground.</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><h4>Bring it on 2012.</h4></blockquote></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social and Gamificaton as Layers]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/13/social-and-gamificaton-as-layers/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-13T04:09:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/13/social-and-gamificaton-as-layers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20111212-knibk1tjsngcpd1y8xcspf7kek.jpg" alt="Layer Cake" /></p>

<h3>Social as a layer</h3>

<p>There has been debate about whether we are at the peak of the social web due to the saturation of social usage.</p>

<p>The truth is that those who think there will be a peak and a slump do not understand social for what it is. As the Zuck would put it: Social is not an app, it is a layer upon the web.</p>

<p>Sure, the web can be served as it is, but social makes it better in a way that is natural to human tendencies and delight. It feeds on mankind&#8217;s tendencies to share things that interests them, thus the power of the &#8220;Like&#8221; and &#8220;Tweet&#8221; buttons. People don&#8217;t need to think about it. It is part of who they are.</p>

<p>A layer doesn&#8217;t make people think. If you are a good designer, you know how important it is to not make users think.</p>

<h3>Gamification as a layer</h3>

<p>I am a web developer and web development is a gamified process where I turn my vision or a mock up into a site. I code it, I click refresh in anticipation of the results and I get to see whether the results match my intended goal. There is constant feedback on my efforts through the refresh button, allowing me to fail and succeed rapidly until I reach the final goal.</p>

<p>And this process is a natural part of the human psych. When we participate in activities we are interested in, we have goals we want to meet, usually related to the mastery of the subject. The best way to meet the goals is to work on it by breaking down the steps into measurable tasks and obtaining feedback on your performance as you complete each task.</p>

<p>A game is defined by 4 traits:</p>

<ol>
<li>Goals</li>
<li>Rules</li>
<li>Feedback</li>
<li>Voluntary Participation</li>
</ol>


<p>It may not be obvious but our life is like a game. We make multiple interesting decisions everyday in order to reach our goals and there are rules that create boundaries to what we can or cannot do to reach them. However, we fail see our lives as game like because of the lack of something that connects the dots for us. Most parts of our lives, we go through them without systematic feedback on our decisions and actions.</p>

<p>Gamification will help solve this lack of feedback. Gamification will be a layer upon our lives and it will be natural to us humans without us having to think about it.</p>

<p>P.S. I don&#8217;t like the word gamification either but the industry seems to have settled on it as the defacto term.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare 3 Elevator Pitches]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/08/prepare-3-elevator-pitches/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-08T03:32:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/08/prepare-3-elevator-pitches</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Always be prepared with 3 elevator pitch for your startup.</p></blockquote>

<p>This was the lesson I learned just 2 days ago. For the past month, I&#8217;ve prepared myself with 2 elevator pitches, one structured to be generic and lasted at most 30s and the other structured to be more specific, with more detail on what the startup actually does and would last from 3 - 5 mins.</p>

<p>When I was asked to give an impromptu 1 min pitch, I was stumped. I went up and tried to fit in as much detail as I could from the longer pitch but I ran over time and what I managed to ramble turned out to be incoherent because I didn&#8217;t manage to get to the point within the minute. That made me realize the importance of the 1 min pitch that I was not prepared for.</p>

<p>I will first outline the 2 pitches I was prepared for:</p>

<ol>
<li>The 30s pitch</li>
<li>The 3-5min pitch</li>
</ol>


<h3>The 30s Elevator Pitch</h3>

<p>The usage of this pitch is pretty clear and straightforward. It&#8217;s for occasions when you have a chance to introduce yourself and what you do but have very limited time with the person you are pitching.</p>

<p>This pitch will be generic but should generate enough interest so the person you pitch is willing to follow up or at the very least, try your product.</p>

<p>The best guide for this I have come across is Adeo Ressi&#8217;s <a href="http://vimeo.com/16447520">Madlibs for Pitching</a> and this is the template to follow:</p>

<p>My company, (company name)<br/>
is developing (a defined offering)<br/>
to help (a target audience)<br/>
(solve a problem)<br/>
(with secret sauce)</p>

<p>Fill in the above and you have a pitch fit for anywhere between 20s to 30s.</p>

<h3>The 3 - 5 min Pitch</h3>

<p>This pitch will require much more detail. And this is the structure that I followed to create my pitch:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start off with an introduction of yourself and the 30s pitch.</li>
<li>What is the problem you are trying to solve?</li>
<li>Explain what your company does to solve the problem.</li>
<li>Talk about your target market and why they will use your solution.</li>
<li>Talk about your competitors and how you will differentiate.</li>
<li>Talk about your revenue model.</li>
<li>Talk about your team and why your team is the best fit to do this.</li>
<li>Talk about what phase you are in and what you need. (eg. Funding? Advice?)</li>
</ol>


<p>There will be quite an amount of detail that you should have done thorough research on, and these are important details that people need to know in order to be truly interested in your business whether they are investors or potential employees. Make sure you know all these information at the tip of your fingers.</p>

<h3>The 1 min Pitch</h3>

<p>There will be times when you will need to give details of your business so that the main points of the business gets across but you have limited time to impress.</p>

<p>This is where the 1 min pitch comes in. Time to put your tweeting skills to use. Be interesting and be concise. Your main goal here is to solicit comments and feedback on top of building interest in what you do.</p>

<p>What does the person you are pitching absolutely has to know in order to understand enough of your business to be able to give valuable feedback?</p>

<p>Here is the structure that I followed to create my 1 min pitch:</p>

<ol>
<li>Introduce yourself and your company.</li>
<li>What is the problem you are trying to solve?</li>
<li>Explain what your company does to solve the problem.</li>
<li>How do you make money?</li>
<li>What do you need from the person you are pitching?</li>
</ol>


<p>The core of this pitch lies in your company&#8217;s solution to the problem described. Get this wrong and be prepared to entertain a befuddled audience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up the blog using Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/07/setting-up-the-blog-using-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-07T13:49:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/12/07/setting-up-the-blog-using-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20111207-p8sni6h2eyyac4dg65wpmpahx8.jpg" alt="Zack's Quest" /></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been wanting to migrate the blog from Wordpress over to a Jekyll/Octopress blogging framework for tech geeks but haven&#8217;t really had the time with my crazy schedules.</p>

<p>And then I realized it doesn&#8217;t actually take too much time to set Octopress up and deploy, especially if you are deploying to Github pages or Heroku.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking to migrate from Wordpress as well, here&#8217;s an outline of the steps I took:</p>

<h4>1. Make sure you have Ruby 1.9.2+ and Clone Octopress</h4>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>git clone git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git octopress
</span><span class='line'>cd octopress</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h4>2. Install dependencies and install the default Ocotpress theme</h4>

<p>bundle install
rake install</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#### 3. Export and convert WordPress blog posts you want to migrate ####
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>Export WordPress blog entries you want to migrate and use [exitwp](https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp) to convert them to markdown.  Put the converted entries into your `source/_posts` folder.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#### 4. Set up a Github page ####
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>If you want a Github page with subdomain called username/organization, set up a Github repository like `username.github.com` or `organization.github.com`
</span><span class='line'>Next, run Octopress's Github Pages setup:
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>rake setup_github_pages</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>It will ask you for your Github repository URL so throw in the SSH URL for your Github repository.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#### 5. Generate the blog and deploy ####
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>rake generate
rake deploy</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#### 6. Commit the source of your blog ####
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>git add .
git commit -m &#8216;your message&#8217;
git push origin source</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>#### 7. View your blog on local ####
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>rake preview
&#8220;`</p>

<h4>8. Set up your custom domain</h4>

<p>I&#8217;ll leave this to you with Octopress&#8217;s own instructions at <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/github#custom_domains">Custom Domains</a>.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plugins un-plugged?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/09/16/plugins-un-plugged/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-16T10:29:11+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/09/16/plugins-un-plugged</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft&#8217;s announcement that plug ins will not be supported in the METRO version of IE10 can be important news, depending on whether or not you believe that METRO will be the UI of the future. The desktop view version of IE10 will
continue to support Flash.</p>

<p>According to their research, 62% of video sites have some form of HTML5 fallback, however we can still be quite sure that a large percentage of sites still use Flash for myriad purposes. One of which is advertising and this will be greatly affected when browsers and devices continuously drops support for Flash, and is likely to happen in the near future judging from recent sentiments. Most advertisements are now done in Flash for the effects that can be created easily using Adobe&#8217;s Flash suite.</p>

<p>The industry will have to step up fast and switch to HTML5 and Javascript for development in the next few years. However, as browsers without plugin support becomes mainstream, I can imagine developers and clients having to spend more time and money on creating both Flash versions and HTML fallback of their
creations.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, it seems like the end of an era is nigh upon us. Web sites and content that load quickly and isn&#8217;t cumbersome should be the focus. The giants have spoken.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby on Rails 3.1 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/31/ruby-on-rails-3-1-released/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-31T11:35:51+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/31/ruby-on-rails-3-1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.skitch.com/20110831-e7yx1i7nqkgtpwwimd9frxd26w.preview.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Hello there!</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been waiting on you a long time now, <a href="http://guides.rubyonrails.org/3_1_release_notes.html">Rails 3.1</a>.</p>

<p>Now now, can&#8217;t wait to get my hands on the latest version of <a href="http://www.manning.com/katz/">Rails 3 in Action</a> and dig my head into Rails 3.1 documentation as well.</p>

<p>I guess my plan to complete Dragon Age : Origins is in ashes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Talkative Developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/the-talkative-developer/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T15:33:43+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/the-talkative-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your job scope requires you to sit behind a huge monitor and bury yourself in code. That basically means you build things, in CODE. And what the code renders, is ART. Interactive art and possibly the most modern, most advanced art form.</p>

<p>As developers, we need to be very talkative about the project we are working on.</p>

<h3>Talk to relevant stakeholders.</h3>

<ul>
<li>Your client, your managers, your peers, tell them what you are doing, solicit feedback.</li>
<li>Tell them your vision.</li>
<li>Tell them what you think would work or won&#8217;t.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t wait till the end to start talking.</li>
<li>Keep communicating. Keep telling.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Talk to other developers.</h3>

<p>Again, tell them what you are doing.
* What technology you are using.
* What language?
* What kind of workflow?
* What have you learned?
* What insights do others have to help improve on the project?</p>

<p>Talk.</p>

<h3>Talk to the public.</h3>

<p>You are Working on an amazing thing. Share what you are doing. Do a show n tell and mostly show how much you love the art you produced.</p>

<ul>
<li>Why do you love it?</li>
<li>Was it the process?</li>
<li>The experimental technology you used?</li>
<li>The people/brand/product behind it?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>Don&#8217;t be a cubicle drone developer. Be a show and tell developer.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hold less poisonous meetings]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/hold-less-poisonous-meetings/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T00:48:51+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/hold-less-poisonous-meetings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unproductive meetings as we know suck up the souls of productive beings. We should always make sure that if we held meetings, they should be meaningful and have a purpose for everyone present. Else, it is way better to drop notes to the other parties and have them read it.</p>

<blockquote><p>No, we do not understand better by talking face to face with each other unless we want to know how each other is feeling about something, or there is
something that needs to be shown.</p></blockquote>

<p>Yes, most meetings are poisonous. It is usually productive time loss of about 30mins to an hour x the number of people in the meeting. So it is always important to think about how important a meeting is.</p>

<p>So before you send out the meeting invite:</p>

<h3>What is it that you want to accomplish in the meeting?</h3>

<p>What is this meeting about? Does everyone know what it is about and why they are at the meeting? Does everyone know what they should take away from the meeting or how they can contribute to it?</p>

<h3>Is it important enough to take away hours of productive time?</h3>

<p>Meet with only those in the team that absolutely needs to be there. Leave the rest alone. If they only need to know the conclusions to the meeting, drop them a note after.</p>

<blockquote><p>An even better way? Just send them a message.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Can what you want to say be understood easily through writing?</h3>

<p>Just go drop a note to the team in short, concise, simple English. They will appreciate it and if they have a question they just have to sound out back to you. What makes you think they will have questions right on the spot anyway?
If they can&#8217;t even process what you&#8217;ve said with ease, they will just be more confused.</p>

<h3>Can what you say be understood better through illustrations?</h3>

<p>Would it be better if you can screenshot / use illustrations to show what you want to say? Send that along. It helps <strong>100%</strong> and more. People are visual creatures. It is much easier to understand something in visual form. Everyone interprets words their own way. Images are concrete. That is why wireframes
work much better than verbal explanations.</p>

<blockquote><p>Seriously, just keep those meetings to a minimum. Highly productive people will appreciate it.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Follow, Google +1 and the other buttons]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/06/03/twitter-follow-google-1-and-the-other-buttons/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-03T18:35:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/06/03/twitter-follow-google-1-and-the-other-buttons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Twitter has launched the “Follow” button.</p>

<p>Using one of our &#8220;favourite&#8221; celebrities as example, clicking on it brings up a pop-up page that allows you to follow a site&#8217;s primary account. (I’m still trying to get the Baby Baby tune out of my head… oh wait… is that girl trying to **** his ear? Damn his twitter page is supposed to be PG!)</p>

<p>The Follow button can and probably will be a new standard button to be used on
campaigns with their dedicated Twitter accounts.</p>

<p>Google’s +1 button is launched as well, which will probably be another standard for digital campaigns and in fact almost most sites will need this due to the possible effects on search ranking.</p>

<p>So now, 5 buttons are important:</p>

<ol>
<li>Twitter Tweet</li>
<li>Twitter Follow</li>
<li>Google +1</li>
<li>Facebook Like</li>
<li>Facebook Recommend</li>
</ol>


<p>Twitter Tweet is important more on a content basis.</p>

<p>Twitter Follow is important for a specific account that belongs to the site. (Campaign account? Brand account?)</p>

<p>Facebook Like/Recommend are pretty well rounded. (Can be for content / site)</p>

<p>Google +1 would be almost everywhere because of effect on search ranking.</p>

<p>What other buttons will come and will future websites be a smorgasbord of all kinds of buttons? I guess for gamers that love Zynga games, that&#8217;ll be a big welcome since they love clicking. Non-stop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google shows it's not easy getting the right cash cow]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/06/01/google-shows-its-not-easy-getting-the-right-cash-cow/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-01T11:03:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/06/01/google-shows-its-not-easy-getting-the-right-cash-cow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google is the perfect example, showing us how difficult it is to get that one product right that will rake in the cash like no tomorrow. Google has developed tons of products as the internet giant it is but its Search and Word Ads are still its main cash cow.</p>

<p>Despite all the innovation one can churn out, it is just that difficult to know what a market would pick up on at a certain time. What I mean to say is that getting that right product fit actually requires a percentage of luck.</p>

<p>Whether you are using the lean startup methodology or the stealth mode mega-launch, the element of luck is there. Lean startup probably helps make sure you at least have a product that someone will be using, but it definitely cannot guarantee that you will grow big.</p>

<p>No one can know for sure what the next big thing is. But like poker, in the lottery of tech startups you just gotta start building for that ticket. Being good multiplies your chances of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noobs should love Coffeescript in Rails 3.1, not hate]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/noobs-should-love-coffeescript-in-rails-3-1-not-hate/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-25T17:40:59+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/25/noobs-should-love-coffeescript-in-rails-3-1-not-hate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I looked at Coffeescript code and loved the neatness and cleanliness of it. So I kept wondering why I read about backlash when it was announced as the standard for Rails 3.1. I did a bit of research and realized that most developers didn&#8217;t want to make big changes to their boiler templates or come up with new ones and opting out through the gemfile was not intuitive. (Or at least these were some of the arguments)</p>

<p>The other was that new people learning Rails would be confused. This I definitely do not agree with because the way that Coffeescript translates to Javascript looks pretty intuitive and the language is easy for new learners to read and understand. I don&#8217;t think it is going to be a barrier for newbies.</p>

<p>I personally like it. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails 3 Cheatsheet by Envy Labs]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/19/5634582064/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-19T04:44:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/05/19/5634582064</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Link: <a href="http://blog.envylabs.com/2010/12/rails-3-cheat-sheets/">Rails 3 Cheatsheet by EnvyLabs</a></p>

<p>Cheatsheets is like a quick reference for newbies like me. This one for Rails
3 by Envy Labs is pure gold.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Desirability]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/creating-desirability/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-15T01:38:38+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/15/creating-desirability</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>“It [Zune] plays music just like an iPod! Why don’t people get this? I don’t know why people want this one chunk of plastic over the chunk of plastic that I make?!” – Bill Gates character in Charlie and the Apple Factory</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Asian Tech Startup Conundrum]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/14/the-asian-tech-startup-conundrum/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-14T21:21:53+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/14/the-asian-tech-startup-conundrum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I read a tweet by <a href="http://twitter.com/jasonong">Jason Ong</a> Singapore Ruby Brigade. He questioned his friend on why he didn&#8217;t pursue starting up a promising idea. His friends answer was : &#8220;can&#8217;t get thru arguing with parents&#8221;</p>

<p>I think that this is a very real issue in an Asian context especially. The importance of family has been embroiled from young and filial piety is of utmost importance. Thus, it is more often than not that parents, even at our modern age, hold big influence on the things we do.</p>

<p>The Asian parents are not unlike those from many other cultures who have slogged their whole lives just so that their family can lead comfortable lives. Those were times when nations were being built and fighting for survival meant more than building empires.</p>

<p>Times have changed but the Asian parents&#8217; minds haven&#8217;t. They still want stable jobs for their kids and thus the best paying jobs like doctors, lawyers and bankers are seen as the best careers to pursue. Entrepreneurship is too risky, especially so in a society that does not accept any form of failure. This concept is proven true by the education systems employed.</p>

<p>Of course, there are also a number of other discouraging factors:</p>

<ol>
<li>There are very few high profile large figure exits that have happened in the region. It might be harder to convince the family the worth of the risk vs the reward.</li>
<li>Pushing beyond the early adopters in the region is comparatively harder. There is a smaller market of early adopters and making early stage survival a tough fight. The rapid take up rate of smartphones might change this however, as apps are easily accessible.</li>
<li>Everyone else in society doesn&#8217;t believe in the path of entrepreneurship. When holding a conversation with an extended family member or their friends and they ask you what you do, if you answer with a full time job where you work hard day and night, they nod their heads with approval that you have found a stable job and are now set for life. If you answered excitedly that you are an entrepreneur and that you are building the next big thing, they&#8217;d likely experience a fluster and a frantic moment hiding their disapproval and wondering how not to look like they are in absolute horror. To the Asian society, being an entrepreneur can almost equate to one not doing any work, or being out of work. In a society where &#8220;face&#8221; is of utmost importance, it becomes all the more difficult. Parents want the easy way out. They want to tell their friends and family that their son/daughter is holding a well paying job.</li>
</ol>


<p>That said, it becomes even more apparent that Asian entrepreneurs have to be a special breed of rebels and revolutionaries who can break past all the difficulties placed to stop them in their tracks.</p>

<p>With enough hunger, I am sure that it is possible to break past &#8220;The Parent Trap&#8221;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS4.3 update arrives to give us Personal Wi-Fi Hotspots]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/10/ios4-3-update-arrives-to-give-us-personal-wi-fi-hotspots/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-10T16:43:28+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/10/ios4-3-update-arrives-to-give-us-personal-wi-fi-hotspots</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- [[![ios4-3](http://zackyap.com/wp-
content/uploads/2011/03/ios4-3.jpg)](http://zackyap.com/wp-
content/uploads/2011/03/ios4-3.jpg)](http://zackyap.com/wp-
content/uploads/2011/03/ios4-3.jpg)
 -->


<p>Image from <a href="http://engadget.com">engadget</a>.Latest iOS update is up and running
and your iPhone should spot an iOS 4.3 software soon.</p>

<p>Why? Checkout the iOS4.3 patch notes. Personal wifi hotspot, which means you
can use your 3G network like a wifi hotspot, giving you 3G connection on the
go as long as you have your iPhone with you.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s not to like about that? Go update nao!!</p>

<blockquote><p>iOS 4.3 Software Update</p></blockquote>

<p>This update contains new features and improvements, including the following:</p>

<p>• Personal Hotspot*  - Share iPhone 4 cellular data connection with up to 5
devices (combination of up to 3 Wi-Fi, 3 Bluetooth,      and 1 USB)</p>

<p>• iTunes Home Sharing  - Play music, movies and TV shows from a shared iTunes
library on a Mac or PC (requires iTunes 10.2)</p>

<p>• New AirPlay features**  - Play videos from the Photos app including the
Camera      Roll album, iTunes previews, enabled third-party apps      and
websites on Apple TV  - Play slideshows from Photos on Apple TV using
transitions available on Apple TV</p>

<p>• Faster Safari performance with Apple Nitro JavaScript   engine</p>

<p>• HD video out using the Apple Digital AV Adapter***  - View 720p HD videos
from Videos app, iPod app,      Photos, YouTube, Safari, Keynote, and enabled
third-party apps on an HDMI display</p>

<p>• Ping features  - Push notifications for comments and follow requests  - Post
and Like songs directly from the Now Playing      screen  - Parental controls•
New Settings  - Messages setting for number of times to repeat an      alert
- iPad side switch setting to lock screen rotation or mute     audio
notifications and sound effects</p>

<p>• Single tap conference call dialing with a pause to send   a passcode</p>

<p>• Bug fixes</p>

<p>Products compatible with this software update:</p>

<p>• iPhone 4 (GSM model)</p>

<p>• iPhone 3GS</p>

<p>• iPad</p>

<p>• iPod touch (4th generation)</p>

<p>• iPod touch (3rd generation)</p>

<p><em>Requires iPhone 4 with tethering data plan<br/>
<strong>Requires Apple TV (2nd generation) running software    version 4.2 or later<br/>
</strong></em>iPhone 4, iPad, iPod touch (4th generation)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[42Goals.com an idea I wanted to work on]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/09/42goals-com-an-idea-i-wanted-to-work-on/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-09T13:12:44+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/03/09/42goals-com-an-idea-i-wanted-to-work-on</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- [![42goals](http://zackyap.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/goals42-300x136.jpg)](http://zackyap.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/goals42.jpg)
 -->


<p>I happened across <a href="http://www.42goals.com">this new web app</a> and through looking at the UI, I know that if I worked on the idea, this would have been what it is.</p>

<p>At its core, it is a goal tracking app where you set up habits that you would like to cultivate and goals you want to achieve. On a daily basis, you would make updates to the app to indicate whether you have achieved your goal.</p>

<p>Initial quick thoughts on this app:</p>

<ol>
<li>It can still be made simpler (simplify the view, really)</li>
<li><del>This would be much better on mobile so that users update on the go</del> (edit: realized they have a mobile version)</li>
<li>Statistics and graphs need to be easy for layman use</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac rumor for today: iPad 2 announcement on 2nd March]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/02/23/mac-rumor-for-today-ipad-2-announcement-on-2nd-march/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-23T17:02:42+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/02/23/mac-rumor-for-today-ipad-2-announcement-on-2nd-march</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest news is that March 2nd&#8217;s Apple event will be for the announcement
of this year&#8217;s iPad. Of course, there are also other rumors that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/09/ipad-3/">this won&#8217;t
be the only release of iPad for the
year</a>, which means that iPad 3 (or
iPad 2.5) will also be released later this year.</p>

<p>This rendition of the iPad is rumored to be faster, includes front and back
cam and comes with high def screen.</p>

<p>Will definitely be up to look at Live Updates on March 2nd night.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
