<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: media, | Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/media-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-23T18:23:59+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Your Product Around Social Status]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/14/build-your-product-around-social-status/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T12:25:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/14/build-your-product-around-social-status</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5025/5684115572_55bc83414f.jpg" alt="Facebook Like Button" /></p>

<p>I have been asking around for why people use foursquare and it is becoming increasingly apparent that game mechanics involving points, badges and mayorship are not the features that keep people checking in.</p>

<p>People are checking in as a show of social status. It shows that they are doing something interesting somewhere. A check in is thus inherently social without the need for badges, mayorship or points.</p>

<p>This is also true for all other social products as the social web is essentially breeding a popularity contest. How many Likes will I get? How many followers do I have? How many people are going to reblog my post? How many karma points will I get?</p>

<p>What people are concerned about on the social web is their social status. The question they are asking can be simplified as "Do people like me?"</p>

<p>If you can build product that helps people get to a "Yes!" for the question above, congratulations! You have an addictive and viral product.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/smemon/5684115572/">Photo Credit</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Verbs are the next big thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/07/verbs-are-the-next-big-thing/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T11:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/07/verbs-are-the-next-big-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2478/3842546304_8c18b824ea.jpg" title="Four Storms And A Twister by JD Hancock under Attribution 2.0 Generic (CC BY 2.0)" alt="Four Storms And A Twister" /></p>

<p>We have seen the value of Likes from the <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1813364/inside-facebook-si-ipo-filing-845-million-users-37-billion-in-revenues-in-2011">S1 filing of Facebook</a> just last week. Facebook has built a multibillion dollar business by understanding what their users say they like, but more importantly they have incorporated <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/opengraph/">Verbs</a> in order to add more context to their users' status updates.</p>

<p>The reason for them doing this is simple really. You can talk about what you Like and think all day but it simply doesn't mean you will act on it. What is a much better indicator of possible behavior is a user's prior behavior. Being able to understand the context of what users are doing will allow advertisers to target users even more accurately.</p>

<p>That is because if you listen to a certain type of music or watch a certain genre of movies frequently, chances are high that you would listen to the same type of music or watch the same genre of movie. Same goes for most lifestyle activities we engage in. Personal preferences are best understood through past behavior.</p>

<p>Activity tracking will be the future and privacy will be compromised. However, in a web eco-system where the social layer drives increasing amount of activity, it is bound to happen.</p>

<p>Activity tracking is not entirely a bad thing however because it provides metrics that provide deeper insights into human behavior and will help us make progress as a species.</p>

<p>In fact, if we are able to create a gamified tracking system that intrinsically rewards users, we will be able to solve much bigger real world problems together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
