<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-09T06:43:46+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time stopped momentarily, I took a glance back at 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/time-stopped/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-15T04:17:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/time-stopped</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reflection is the first step for improvement. Without spending time to figure out what to learn and improve on, we fall into the danger of stagnation. This may come a little late but it must be done. Let's take a look back at my 2011.</p>

<h3>1. Toy with idea of Gamification</h3>

<p>It was the beginning of a new year. Being an RPG lover, I started imagining living my life as if it was an RPG, gaining levels while completing quests and achievements.</p>

<p>I was sure it was a novel idea but some research proved that it was not. SCVNGR was the biggest real life Gamification service at that time.</p>

<p>My first thought was that I wanted to marry Gamification with instagram's stickiness as an app. Sourcing for funding was a tough matter at that time and I was unsure how to move the idea forward. It probably sucked anyway, as all who have experience in tech startups would tell you about your initial idea.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: Fund raising is a difficult process for early stage ideas and first time founders. Get a working prototype out!</p>

<h3>2. Account executive work</h3>

<p>I continued my work as an account executive and learned a lot about customer service and project management, though project management was mostly planning what the client wanted.</p>

<p>During this time, I also discovered my love for coding as I made amendments to my developers' code due to tight timelines.</p>

<p>I loved building things. I knew this subconsciously but I was afraid of failing as I never had prior experience, but I took my first step towards development by asking for a switch of department.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: If you want something, dare to ask for it. If you never take that step, no one can help you get what you want.</p>

<h3>3. Hunger to be a web developer</h3>

<p>I was filled with the hunger to develop for the web and devoured knowledge of HTML5 &amp; CSS3 like a famished vulture. I began picking up jQuery for how easy it was to add interaction to sites and I slowly transitioned into the role of a web developer.</p>

<p>I had little time to sleep as I juggled the extra load of learning but I thoroughly enjoyed the learning process.</p>

<p>Lesson Learned: Coding is a creative and iterative process. It takes awhile to get the code right sometimes but the winning sensation is immensely gratifying.</p>

<p>Also, coder's block is extremely dangerous and causes me to visit Hacker News more times than I should.</p>

<h3>4. Founder Institute</h3>

<p>During the last quarter of 2011, I received news that I got accepted into Fall 2011's SG FI batch. I jumped on the opportunity with only the slightest of hesitation. (ok, just a bit of research on Quora before I paid the course fees.)</p>

<p>Q4 of 2011 would prove to be the toughest period of 2011 for me as I juggled the course schedule, the assignments and an intensive work schedule on my day job doing web development. Few hours of sleep with lots of late night discussions, brainstorming and coding became the norm.</p>

<p>It is paying off now as I am about to start working on Questified full time, taking the full plunge into entrepreneurship.</p>

<p>Founder Institute has been the forceful helping hand that's pushing my non-functioning aircraft off the edge. I am all ready to start the sprint to make sure the air craft can fly before it hits the ground.</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><h4>Bring it on 2012.</h4></blockquote></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
