<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups, | Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/startups-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-09T06:56:23+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startup Name-jutsu]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/startup-name-jutsu/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T06:25:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/startup-name-jutsu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3202/3047945096_b287e7ec97_b.jpg" alt="aafad 186/365 teenage mutant haunted turtle" /></p>

<h3>Naming is a bitch</h3>

<p>We've found a name for our product but the process of naming a startup in this day and age is crazy tough especially if you are on the web. I'm not talking about a player scoring 40 points in one NBA game kind of tough. I'm talking about a player scoring 80 points in one game kind of tough. There are a few well known reasons for this and that includes the need to get the following (in order of importance):</p>

<ol>
<li>Domain Name (that is preferably .com)</li>
<li>Twitter and Facebook</li>
<li>Other social media account namespaces</li>
</ol>


<h3>Head Bang!</h3>

<p>While looking for a good name for our product, we were banging our heads on walls at first, randomly plucking names from thin air that we thought matched what we were doing. During this time, we used name.com, godaddy.com and namecheap.com to check domain availability.</p>

<p>Many hours were lost on the fact that we wanted to settle with a name that all 3 co-founders would share an affinity to. We wanted to make sure that we would all love it and infuse the name with our heart, soul and personality.</p>

<h3>Read these for a better name</h3>

<p>We decided that we needed more help, so we went through a number of resources that would give us insights into good names for modern startups:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.quora.com/How-did-DAngelo-and-Cheever-come-up-with-the-name-Quora">How did D'Angelo and Cheever come up with the name Quora?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hopperanddropper.com/syllables-scrabble-letters-and-picking-brand-names/">Syllables, Scrabble Letters, and Picking Brand Names</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/05/startup-names/">How Today’s Hottest Startups Got Their Names</a></li>
<li><a href="http://onstartups.com/tabid/3339/bid/17702/17-Mutable-Suggestions-For-Naming-A-Startup.aspx">17 Mutable Suggestions For Naming A Startup</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.asmartbear.com/naming-startup.html">Naming your startup: Settle down, it’s cool!</a></li>
</ol>


<h3>Another Round?</h3>

<p>And so we tried again and on our second round, we started with some criteria that'd we'd like to have for THE name. The name should be</p>

<ol>
<li>2 or 3 syllables</li>
<li>Spellable</li>
<li>Not commonly used by a well known company</li>
<li>Makes sense for our product</li>
</ol>


<p>We didn't mind made up words and we started using our list of culture and product description words to try to come up with more names whether made up or not.</p>

<h3>Namestation.com</h3>

<p>A tool that really made things easy was <a href="http://www.namestation.com">Namestation.com</a>. It has various ways to help you brainstorm for names including adding popular prefixes and suffixes, combining words in customizes lists, blending words from custom lists with top 1000 keywords, alliterations and many others. On top of that, it does domain checking for each name which cut down the time and effort needed by another 20%. I highly recommend startups to check it out if you are having trouble finding a name.</p>

<h3>X-Factor</h3>

<p>The final step of our naming equation was a Reality TV type game where we were the Startup Name X-Factor judges. Through the help of NameStation, we created a master list of over 500 names together with our original list and we put the list of names into a Google Docs worksheet. We would then give an X each for names we would like to pass. To stay on the list, the name needed at least 2 votes based on our judgement using the criteria we listed. We did 3 rounds to cut the list down to the Final 10 before we discussed the pros and cons of each and finally picking the one we all loved.</p>

<p>That was a mega rant of our naming process. So what's the name we picked? We'll let you know once when the launch page is up. Until then, hang on tight and get ready for an adventure of a lifetime!</p>

<h3>tl;dr</h3>

<blockquote><h4>Recommended Steps to Find a Name</h4>

<ol>
<li>Read the posts listed above</li>
<li>Pick criteria for the name</li>
<li>Use a tool like <a href="http://www.namestation.com">NameStation.com</a> to brainstorm and generate names</li>
<li>Use a voting system to cut the list down according to criteria picked</li>
<li>Talk through the final list</li>
<li>You have a name. Congrats!</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/theshadowknows/3047945096/">Photo Credit</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship: A Path of Self Discovery]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/entrepreneurship-a-path-of-self-discovery/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T17:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/entrepreneurship-a-path-of-self-discovery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Met a friend who's been running a business for awhile. He looked at me and said, "Heard you're doing a startup for the first time. Congratulations, but be warned that the first year will be all about self discovery."</p>

<p>It is now my 4th day of working on my startup full time and I get what he's talking about. It probably won't be just a one year thing.</p>

<p>Nothing you have ever done will prepare you as a first time founder for the amount of introspection and self reflection you will do because you are constantly making decisions. And you'd be lying if you say you always know you are making the best choice.</p>

<p>That is probably why so many of us turn to <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> and other startup blogs to seek crowdsourced wisdom from people who think they've got it right.</p>

<p>The truth is that we will almost never have a damned clue over whether our decisions are the best but we can definitely wish that they lead to the best outcome.</p>

<p>What we can do for ourselves is to make decisions in a lean and agile manner just like how we want to run our startups. Early on, make decisions based on your hunch and keep iterating depending on the results.</p>

<p>Be flexible and be smart about it. We are in the school of hard knocks and there's no way around getting hurt in the process of starting a company. We just need to keep optimizing and learning.</p>

<p>Good game and good luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
