<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups, | Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/startups-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-23T18:30:30+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship: A Path of Self Discovery]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/entrepreneurship-a-path-of-self-discovery/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T17:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/entrepreneurship-a-path-of-self-discovery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Met a friend during my weekly basketball session last night who's been running a business for awhile. He looked at me and said, "Heard you're doing a startup for the first time. Congratulations, but be warned that the first year will be all about self discovery."</p>

<p>It is now my 4th day of working on my startup full time and I get what he's talking about. It probably won't be just a one year thing.</p>

<p>Nothing you have ever done will prepare you as a first time founder for the amount of introspection and self reflection you will do because you are constantly making decisions. And you'd be lying if you say you always know you are making the best choice.</p>

<p>That is probably why so many of us turn to <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com">Hacker News</a> and other startup blogs to seek crowdsourced wisdom from people who think they've got it right.</p>

<p>The truth is that we will almost never have a damned clue over whether our decisions are the best but we can definitely wish that they lead to the best outcome.</p>

<p>What we can do for ourselves is to make decisions in a lean and agile manner just like how we want to run our startups. Early on, make decisions based on your hunch and keep iterating depending on the results.</p>

<p>Be flexible and be smart about it. We are in the school of hard knocks and there's no way around getting hurt in the process of starting a company. We just need to keep optimizing and learning.</p>

<p>Good game and good luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
