<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Management | Zack's Questlog]]></title>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/categories/management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-13T17:53:43+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zackyap.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zack Yap -- @zackyap]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hold less poisonous meetings]]></title>
    <link href="http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/hold-less-poisonous-meetings/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T00:48:51+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zackyap.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/hold-less-poisonous-meetings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unproductive meetings as we know suck up the souls of productive beings. We should always make sure that if we held meetings, they should be meaningful and have a purpose for everyone present. Else, it is way better to drop notes to the other parties and have them read it.</p>

<blockquote><p>No, we do not understand better by talking face to face with each other unless we want to know how each other is feeling about something, or there is
something that needs to be shown.</p></blockquote>

<p>Yes, most meetings are poisonous. It is usually productive time loss of about 30mins to an hour x the number of people in the meeting. So it is always important to think about how important a meeting is.</p>

<p>So before you send out the meeting invite:</p>

<h3>What is it that you want to accomplish in the meeting?</h3>

<p>What is this meeting about? Does everyone know what it is about and why they are at the meeting? Does everyone know what they should take away from the meeting or how they can contribute to it?</p>

<h3>Is it important enough to take away hours of productive time?</h3>

<p>Meet with only those in the team that absolutely needs to be there. Leave the rest alone. If they only need to know the conclusions to the meeting, drop them a note after.</p>

<blockquote><p>An even better way? Just send them a message.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Can what you want to say be understood easily through writing?</h3>

<p>Just go drop a note to the team in short, concise, simple English. They will appreciate it and if they have a question they just have to sound out back to you. What makes you think they will have questions right on the spot anyway?
If they can't even process what you've said with ease, they will just be more confused.</p>

<h3>Can what you say be understood better through illustrations?</h3>

<p>Would it be better if you can screenshot / use illustrations to show what you want to say? Send that along. It helps <strong>100%</strong> and more. People are visual creatures. It is much easier to understand something in visual form. Everyone interprets words their own way. Images are concrete. That is why wireframes
work much better than verbal explanations.</p>

<blockquote><p>Seriously, just keep those meetings to a minimum. Highly productive people will appreciate it.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
